livebinders.com 2018-12-10

# LiveBinders Privacy Policy

May 25, 2018

## LiveBinders Privacy Policy

The following Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy” or “privacy policy”) governs our storage and use of the information you provide to us during your use of the LiveBinders (DOT) com website, and all content, services and/or products available thereon (collectively, the "Services.").

This privacy policy describes LiveBinders’ information gathering and dissemination practices with respect to information we collect through our Services. Because the Internet is global, information about you that we collect or that you submit may be transferred to, processed in, and held in countries (including the United States) other than the one in which you reside. By using our Services, you explicitly consent to such use of your information and agree to the terms of this privacy policy.

## Information You Choose to Submit

You can use our Services without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information (which we will refer to in this privacy policy as "Personal Data") about yourself. To obtain access to certain areas of our Services, however, or to receive certain services we provide (e.g., creating a livebinder, installing an application, upgrading to a premium service), you may be required to register with us and, in connection with such registration, to provide certain Personal Data (e.g., your full name, email address, billing information). We use such information to provide you with the services and features you requested or registered for, and to monitor internally the usage of our Services. We also use such information to fulfill your order and to contact you from time to time about us, about your support questions, about our website, and about our products and services. 

  * **Registration:** If you desire to have access to restricted sections of our Services, you may be required to become a registered user, and to submit any of the following: email, username, password, district, school, company name, city. Note: We encrypt your passwords.
  * **Customer Support:** We may collect information through your communications with our customer support team or other communications that you may send us and their contents.
  * **Temporary Passwords:** You may request a temporary password to be sent to the email on your account. It is your responsibility to change your password once you log in. We delete temporary passwords.
  * **Email Notifications:** You must opt-in to receive email notifications regarding marketing communications about products, services, offers, programs and promotions of LiveBinders and affiliated companies. To change your opt-in status please go to the Email Notifications box from your My Profile page. Even if you do opt-out of email notifications, we reserve the right to send you administrative messages relating to our Services (e.g., about changes to this privacy policy, maintenance issues), to contact you regarding orders you have placed (e.g., order confirmations), and to share your information with our service providers as necessary to provide you with the Services.
  * **Purchase or Upgrade:** When you make payments through the Service, you will need to provide Personal Data such as a credit card number and billing address. We use a 3rd party service to process your payments and do not store your credit card information. We require these third parties to maintain the privacy and security of the Personal Data they process on our behalf.
  * **Social Media Posts:** We offer you the ability to post your LiveBinder links directly to your social media account. In order to allow you to post to your social media platforms, we may direct you to their log in page to provide username, account IDs, social handle and email address. We refer you to their Privacy policies for handling your login credentials.
  * **Access to Connected Storage Sites:** We give you the opportunity to connect content from other third party media storage sites. Please refer to **_"Information We Get From Connected Social Media Partners"_** section below.

## Information We Get From Connected Social Media Partners

### Google Login and Google Drive

You can log into LiveBinders using single sign-on services such as Google Login. We use these services only to authenticate your identity and provide you the option to add selected content links from your Google Drive directly into your LiveBinder tabs. We do not keep or store any of your login credentials.

### Dropbox

You can log into your Dropbox account within your LiveBinders editor. We use these services only to authenticate your identity and provide you the option to add selected content links from your Dropbox account directly into your LiveBinder tabs. We do not keep or store any of your login credentials.

### Social Media Widgets

Our website includes social media features and widgets, such as the “Share This” button. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. You must be logged into your social media account, outside of the LiveBinders platform, in order to share a post on your feed. Your interactions with these third party sites are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them as listed below. We do not store or keep any third party login credentials including the following:

## Information We Automatically Collect

### Cookies

We automatically collect certain information to help us understand how visitors use our website and product (which we will refer to in this privacy policy as "Usage Data"). We use cookies (which are small amounts of data sent from a web server to your browser that are stored on your mobile device or computer's hard drive) to keep track of your use of our Services, to validate your identity, to maintain login sessions and remember preferences, to tailor our Services to meet your personal interests, and to improve the quality of our Services. 

### Third Party Cookies

Our Services allows members to link other websites in their binders. Cookies set by these third party websites are governed by the privacy policies of those third party websites. These websites may also collect information through cookies.

We do not currently place ads in our Services, but we reserve the right to do so, and in those cases, those advertisements may collect information through cookies to ensure that their advertising systems are working properly and to track responses to their advertisements.

We use Google Analytics to track visitor behavior. Each time you visit our website we automatically collect your IP address, browser type and computer type, access time, the webpage from which you came, and webpage(s) that you access during your visit.

From time to time, LiveBinders may partner with third party affiliate programs including iTunes and Amazon Affiliate programs where we may earn commissions on items purchased from within our Services. Those third party programs may use cookies to track where the orders are generated from within our Services. 

Generally, you can set your browser not to accept cookies or to notify you if you are sent a cookie, giving you the opportunity to choose whether or not to accept the cookie. Please note that if you do set your browser not to accept cookies, certain areas of our website may not function properly and we may not be able to provide you with certain features of the Services.

## How We May Use Your Personal Data

We may use Personal Data to: 

  * Create and manage your account, provide our Service, process payments, and respond to your inquiries
  * Communicate with you to verify your account and for informational and operational purposes, such as account management, customer service or system maintenance, including by periodically emailing you service-related announcements
  * Tailor our Service (e.g., we may use cookies and similar technologies to remember your preferences)
  * Publish your content, comments or messages on social media platforms
  * Provide customer support
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including by developing new products and services; managing our communications; determining the effectiveness of our advertising; analyzing how the Service is being accessed and used; tracking performance of the Service; debugging the Service; facilitating the use of our Service)
  * After choosing to "opt-in" to be notified, send you email regarding marketing communications about products, services, offers, programs and promotions of LiveBinders and affiliated companies
  * Enforce our agreements related to our Service and our other legal rights
  * Apply with applicable legal requirements, industry standards and our policies

## How We Share Your Personal Data

Generally, we will not share your Personal Data or Usage Data with any third party without your permission, except as otherwise described in this section of our privacy policy.

**Aggregated Data.** We use Google Analytics to understand when, where and how visitors use our site. We have in the past, and may in the future, offer reports to paid subscribers that help them understand the visitor behavior for a particular binder they've created. Google uses cookies placed on our website to help us track visitor behavior. To understand how Google uses your Personal Data, we refer to Google's [privacy policies.](https://policies.google.com/privacy)

**Service Providers.** From time to time, we may enter into relationships with third parties who provide services to us (e.g., credit card processing services, web services, email services, support management services or data management and storage services). In those circumstances, we disclose information about you that is necessary for such service providers to perform those services, but only if such service providers agree not to disclose your information except as necessary to perform such services. 

**Other Disclosure Scenarios.** Notwithstanding anything in this privacy policy to the contrary, we reserve the right, unless limited by applicable law, to share any information we have collected about you or that you have submitted: 

  1. in response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims
  2. if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, fraud, or situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or property
  3. if we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding situations that involve significant abuse of our website infrastructure or the Internet in general (such as voluminous spamming, denial of service attacks, or attempts to compromise the security of information)
  4. to our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with us (in which case we will require such entities to honor this privacy policy); and
  5. with another entity that acquires or merges with us.

## Public Areas

Your use of areas of our website that are intended for interaction with other users (e.g., message boards, discussion rooms, and other online forums) may allow you to post Personal Data. By choosing to use these areas, you understand and agree that anyone may access, use, and disclose any Personal Data that you post to those areas.

## Choice/Opt-Out

We offer you the opportunity to choose not to receive communications from us. If you would like to take advantage of this opportunity, please let us know by updating your My Profile page on our website. Please note that sometimes these requests may take up to ten business days to process, and that we are not responsible for removing information about you from the database of any third party with which we shared your Personal Data prior to processing your request. Even if you do take advantage of this opportunity, we reserve the right to send you administrative messages relating to our Services (e.g., about changes to this privacy policy, maintenance issues), to contact you regarding orders you have placed (e.g., order confirmations), and to share your information with our service providers as necessary to provide you with the Services.

## Accessing, Correcting, and Deleting Your Personal Data

If you would like to modify your account information, please update it on your My Profile page. If you would like any Personal Data you previously submitted to us deleted, please let us know by sending us an email to privacy (at) LiveBinders (DOT) com. (Please send your request from the email address associated with your account and clearly state what Personal Data you would like modified or deleted).

We also take measures to delete your Personal Data or keep it in a form that does not permit identifying you when this information is no longer necessary for the purposes for which we process it, unless we are required by law to keep this information for a longer period. When determining the retention period, we take into account various criteria, such as the type of product and services requested by or provided to you, the nature and length of our relationship with you, possible re-enrollment with our products or services, the impact on the services we provide to you if we delete some information from or about you, mandatory retention periods provided by law and the statute of limitations. 

Please note that sometimes these requests may take up to thirty business days to process, that any Personal Data that we have copied may remain in back-up storage for some period of time after your request, and that if you delete certain information (e.g., your billing address) you may not be able to purchase products in the future without re-submitting such information. Also, please note that we will maintain information about you in our database for accounting purposes or whenever we are required to do so by law.

## How We Protect Your Personal Information

We have implemented reasonable measures to help protect your Personal Data from loss, misuse, or unauthorized access or disclosure. We employ administrative and electronic measures designed to appropriately protect your Personal Data against accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, unauthorized alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, misuse, and any other unlawful form of processing of the Personal Data in our possession. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot ensure or warrant that information about you will not be accessed, viewed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our administrative, physical and electronic safeguards, subject to requirements under applicable law to guarantee information.

We will make any legally-required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted, electronically stored Personal Data to you via email or conspicuous posting on our website in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system, and any other discloures that may be required under applicable law.

## Children Safety

If students are under 13 years of age, they must have parental permission to register an account at LiveBinders. Schools should obtain parental permission before issuing accounts to students. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has a registered account for the Services or that we have received any Personal Data of that child without your consent, then you may alert us through your school administrator and have them contact us at info (at) livebinders (DOT) com and request that we delete that child’s Personal Data and/or account from our systems.

## Links to Other Websites

Our Services may contain links to other websites.

WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE INFORMATION COLLECTION, USE, DISCLOSURE OR OTHER PRIVACY PRACTICES OF ANY THIRD PARTY, INCLUDING OUR AFFILIATES, THIRD-PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS, ANY THIRD-PARTY SOCIAL MEDIA PLATFORM, ANY THIRD PARTY MAKING AVAILABLE THE DEVICES OR OPERATING SYSTEMS FOR WHICH THE SITE IS AVAILABLE, AND ANY THIRD PARTY OPERATING ANY WEBSITE TO WHICH THE SITE CONTAINS A LINK. YOU MAY HAVE RIGHTS DIRECTLY ENFORCEABLE AGAINST THESE THIRD PARTIES SO YOU SHOULD CONSIDER THEIR PRIVACY POLICIES TO LEARN MORE.

We urge you to review such practices prior to submitting any personal information to such websites.

## International Users

If you choose to use the Services from the European Union or other regions of the world with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, then please note that you are transferring your personally identifiable information outside of those regions to the United States and by providing your personally identifiable information on or through the Services you consent to that transfer.

## Changes

We may update this privacy policy from time to time. If under any such update we make any material change to the way in which we treat your Personal Data or Usage Data, we will inform you of such change via email or by posting a notice on relevant areas of our Services. Any updated version of this privacy policy will be effective as of the date set forth therein.

## Uploaded Content

To learn more about Document Security for your uploaded content click here.

## More Information

If you have additional questions, please contact us any time. Or write to us at:

Privacy Matters  
c/o LiveBinders Inc.  
795 Folsom Street, 1st Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94107
